今天我们继续讨论规格
Today we're continuing our discussion of specifications
通过更多地讨论规范的属性
by talking more about the properties of specs
是什么使一些规格比其他规格更好。
and what makes some specs better than other ones.
读完这篇文章，你应该
After this reading, you should be
能够理解不够坚决
able to understand under determined
规范；能够识别和评估非决定论；
specs; be able to identify and assess non-determinism;
应该理解声明性和操作性规范
should understand declarative and operational specs
能够编写声明性规范；
and be able to write declarative specs;
应该了解先决条件的强度，
should understand the strength of preconditions,
岗位条件和规格；能够比较规格
post-conditions, and specs; be able to compare specifications
优点；你应该能写
strengths; you should be able to write
适当强度的连贯有用的规范。
coherent useful specifications of appropriate strength.
好 啊。
OK.
我们开始吧。
Let's get started.